A Guide to the Elizabeth Archer Barnard Nickels Papers, 1941-1990
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Elizabeth Archer Barnard Nickels Papers, 1941-1990
The Library of Virginia
44881, 45351
28 cubic feet (25 boxes and 93 oversize folders)
Nickels, Elizabeth Archer Barnard, 1918-2012
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Crown Collectibles, Chesterfield, Virginia, 2010.
Biographical Information
Elizabeth "Beth" Archer Barnard was born on 14 September 1918 at her family home, "Sunnyside," in Prince George County, Virginia. Her mother, Judith Fenner Barnard (1896-1984) was a school teacher for Prince George County Schools and her father, Edgar C. Barnard (b. 1895), was a traveling civil engineer. In 1926, Edgar moved away from Virginia, leaving Beth and her mother at "Sunnyside" with their extended family. He left his drafting equipment to Beth. From an early age she demonstrated a talent for drawing with measured straight lines rather than artistically. Attributing this skill to her father, she wanted to follow in a similar path of engineering or design. Beth's mother and grandmother, however, wanted to see her pursue a career in teaching, as they had. In 1935, Beth graduated from Hopewell High School and enrolled in Farmville State Teachers College. After two years, she transferred to William & Mary College where she excelled in Latin and Mathematics. Beth received her Bachelor of Arts degree in Mathematics in June 1939.
After graduation, Beth accepted a teaching position in Lancaster County, Virginia, for $80 a month. In 1940, she switched to the Surry County school system in order to be closer to home. As men began leaving the workforce for wartime enrollment in the armed services, expanded educational and career opportunities were available to women. Teaching during the day, Beth enrolled in engineering and drafting classes offered at night in Hopewell.
In 1942, Beth accepted her first job as a draftsman for the chemical plant Solvay Process Company (Allied Chemical) in Hopewell. She was not entirely satisfied with this position because it did not allow for any creativity. This same year she met Samuel B. Nickels, Jr. (1918-2001), a second lieutenant in the U.S. Army. They married on 11 July 1942 in what Beth called her "7-11 Wedding." Beth resigned from Solvay once they were married and spent a year traveling with Sam before he was deployed for service abroad.
During Sam's absence she accepted a position at Camp Lee in the Post Engineer's office. Upon his return in 1946, she went to work as a storefront designer for Binswanger Glass Company. She loved the work and the ability to use both her creativity and her technical skills. When she learned that her salary was only half of what her male colleagues earned, she sought employment elsewhere.
In 1948, Beth went to work for a small architectural firm in Richmond as a draftsman and shortly after was discovered by architect Marcellus Wright Sr. He realized the importance of having a woman on his team as her designs would appeal to the wives of his wealthy clients. Working as a a draftsman and project manager for Marcellus Wright & Son beginning in 1947, she specialized in prominent residential design, specifically in the Windsor Farms area of Richmond. The majority of the collection of her papers at the Library of Virginia features her residential designs and specifications for these grand homes.
Throughout this time, the building industry experienced many booms as well as slower times. During the slow times architectural draftsmen were often "lent" out to other firms to aid with projects. Through this she had the opportunity to work with many other architects, including Frederick Hyland. Beth enjoyed working with Hyland as his ideas were innovative and unprecedented. In her words, she "liked his ideas...They didn't always work, but I liked them." Her efforts at other firms are also seen in the Library of Virginia's collection of her papers, as it houses many plans from these architects.
In 1962, Beth wanted to gain more experience in the technical side of the field. Carl Torrence with the engineering firm Torrence, Dreelin & Associates convinced Beth to join their team. Here she designed the facades and entrances for many modern industrial buildings throughout the city. She experienced great freedom of design choice as they allowed her to adorn their buildings as she saw fit with very little design interference from the engineers. Beth worked with this firm until 1968, rounding out a 20-year career in residential and commercial architectural drafting.
In this same year she switched gears and accepted a job teaching drafting at the Richmond Technical School. Here she could combine her talents with her innate ability to teach. She was held in highest esteem by her students and their efforts won them national awards in competitions held throughout the country. Nickels retired from teaching in 1985.
Beth's prolific contribution to the architectural industry of Virginia is evident in the numerous plans, drawings, elevations, specifications, and correspondence from her career. While not a registered architect, Beth Nickels's contribution to the architectural field was significant. Nickels is recognized as one of the first women in the Richmond area to work in the architectural field. Her work can be seen today throughout the City of Richmond, as many of her buildings are still standing (as of publication of this finding aid, 2012). Her teaching efforts provided the builders of today with their interest in the industry and their foundational skills. Most importantly, the plans and correspondence that she saved provide great insight into the building industry of Richmond in the mid-20th century and without them a portion of history would be lost.
Elizabeth "Beth" Archer Barnard Nickels passed away at "Sunnyside" on 21 March 2012.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1941-1990, of Elizabeth "Beth" Archer Barnard Nickels (1918-2012), consist of materials documenting her education, life, and career. Included are personal and professional correspondence related to her work with various architectural firms and for the Richmond Technical Center; trade catalogues and journals; specifications by firm and project; photographs; letterhead; pay stubs; drawings and plans; sketches; maps; and student drafting projects.
While the contents of this collection mainly reflect Nickels's professional career, a significant collection of personal letters between Beth, her husband, parents, and friends can be found in the Barnard-Nickels Family Papers (LVA Accession 44954).
Arrangement
The collection originally was sorted by firm and miscellaneous drawings by the collector, but contained no chronological order so an arrangement consisting of four series was imposed by the interning archivist.
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I. Professional and Office Correspondence, 1949-1989.
II. Industry Trade Catalogues and Journals.
III. Specifications, 1948-1968.
IV. Project Files, 1941-1990.
Contents List
- Series I. Professional and Office Correspondence, 1949-1989. (Box 1-3, 8-10)
  Series I consists of personal and professional correspondence relating to Elizabeth Archer Barnard Nickels's career. The documents are arranged into three subseries, divided by employing firm or school. Within each subseries, the files are arranged chronologically. Office memos, phone messages, and photographs are contained in this series.
  - Subseries I.A. - Marcellus Wright & Son Architectural Firm.
    - Correspondence, 1946-1949. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1950. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1951. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1952. (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
    - Correspondence, 1953. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1954. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1955. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1956. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1957. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1958. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1959. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1960. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1961-1965. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, miscellaneous. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Photographs. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Stationery and change order forms. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Subseries I.B. - Torrence, Dreelin & Associates.
    - Correspondence, 1961-1963. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1967. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1968-1971. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Subseries I.C. - Richmond Technical Center.
    Correspondence related to the Richmond Technical Center.
    Arranged chronologically.
    - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence, 1969 (Folder 3-4)
    - Correspondence, Jan.-April 1970 (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
    - Correspondence, May-Dec. 1970 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1979-1989 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence and educational publications, undated (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
    - Binder (deconstructed): Course of Study for Architectural Drafting, prepared by Beth Nickels, May 1969 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Binder: Competency-based Vocational Education, undated (Box 10)
    - Binder: Vocational Education Special Programs (prepared by the Dept. of Industrial Education and Technology, Virginia State University), undated. (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Series II. Industry Trade Catalogues and Journals. (Box 11-21)
  Series II contains an extensive collection of trade catalogues and journals. The catalogues are manufacturer-specific and are arranged by subject or specialty (Subseries II.A). The industry journals are ordered alphabetically by title (Subseries II.B).
  - Subseries II.A. - Trade catalogues.
    Arranged by subject.
    - Baths/Kitchens. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Cement/Stone/Tile. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Insulation/Weather-proofing. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Land use. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Wood. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Glass/Windows. (Box 12, Folder 1-4)
    - Roofs/Ceilings/Walls. (Box 12, Folder 5-6)
    - House Plans/Pattern Books. (Box 13)
    - Interior Design/HVAC. (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous trade publications. (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous monographs. (Box 16)
  - Subseries II.B. - Trade journals.
    Arranged alphabetically.
    - A-B. (Box 17)
    - E. (Box 18)
    - P. (Box 19)
    - R-U. (Box 20)
    - Oversized journals. (Box 21)
- Series III. Specifications, 1948-1968. (Box 3-5)
  This series contains numerous specifications for various projects and corresponding drawings and project files. The specifications are arranged by employing firm. Specifications relating to Marcellus Wright & Son are arranged chronologically in Subseries III.A. Torrence, Dreelin & Associates specifications are contained in Subseries III.B and are also arranged chronologically. In the latter portion of Nickels's career, she was involved with subdivision developing throughout Prince George County. Specifications and correspondence related to this work can be found in Subseries III.C.
  - Subseries III.A. - Marcellus Wright & Son.
    - Residence for Col. and Mrs. Hancock Reed, Old Gun Road, Chesterfield, Virginia, 1948. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Residence for Mr. and Mrs. H. Grandis, 4 Greenway Lane, Hampton Gardens, Richmond, Virginia, 1949. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Residence for Mr. and Mrs. L. H. Jenkins, Jr., Calycanthus Road and Lilac Lane, Windsor Farms, Richmond, Virginia, 1949. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Residence for Mr. and Mrs. Samuel B. Nickels, Jr., Sunnyside, Prince George, Virginia, 1949. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Residence for Miss Agnes Jacob, Midlothian, Virginia, 1949. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Residence for Mr. and Mrs. Tazewell Carrington, III, Old Orchard Lane, Hillcrest, Richmond, Virginia, 1951. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Residence for Dr. Benjamin W. Rawles, Jr., 2306 Monument Avenue, Richmond, Virginia, 1951. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Residence for Mr. and Mrs. Lloyd U. Noland, Jr., James River Drive, Warwick-on-the-James, Warwick, Virginia, 1953. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Residence for Mr. and Mrs. Charles A. Straus, Overlook Road, Henrico County, Virginia, 1953. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Residence for Mr. and Mrs. George Allen, Jr., 213 Lock Lane, Windsor Farms, Richmond, Virginia, 1954. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Residence for Mr. and Mrs. Thomas P. Bryan, Jr., 5 Greenway Lane, Hampton Gardens, Richmond, Virginia, 1954. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Residence for Dr. W. D. Suggs, 1213 West Franklin Street, Richmond, Virginia, 1955. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Residence for Mr. and Mrs. Robert K. Williams, Dover & Nottingham, Windsor Farms, Richmond, Virginia, 1955. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Annex building for Hopewell Furniture Company, Hopewell Virginia, 1955. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Residence for Mr. and Mrs. Russell C. Scott, Tempsford Lane, Richmond, Virginia, 1955. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Residence for Mr. and Mrs. Edgar B. Boynton, Tempsford Lane, Richmond, Virginia, 1955. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Residence for Mr. and Mrs. John H. Krey, 5504 Matoaka Road, Richmond, Virginia, 1956. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Residence for Mrs. John G. Pollard, 1015 W. Franklin Street, Richmond, Virginia, 1957. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Tennis Shop for Country Club of Virginia, St. Andrews Lane, Richmond, Virginia, 1959. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Medical Office Buildings for Drs. Thornton & Howlette, 206-208 E. Clay Street, Richmond, Virginia, 1961. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Subseries III.B. - Torrence, Dreelin & Associates.
    - Offices at 1112 E. Main St., Richmond, Virginia, 1963. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Offices for 2nd & Cary Street Corp., Northwest Corner of 2nd & Cary Street, Richmond, Virginia, 1964. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Inta-Bota Machine Company Inc., Byrd Airport, Richmond, Virginia, 1964. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Warehouse and offices for M & M Industries, Ashland, Virginia, 1964. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Dock addition for Transcon Lines, 506 East Clopton Street, Richmond, Virginia, 1965. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Pat's One Stop, Richmond, Virginia, 1965. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Morgan's Drug Store, Gloucester, Virginia, 1965. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Addition to Southern Special Products, 3021 Vernon Road, Henrico County, Virginia, 1966. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Factory for E. R. Carpenter Co., Temple, Texas, 1966. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Southern Biscuit Company, Myers Street, Richmond, Virginia, 1968. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous, undated. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Subseries III.C. - Specifications and correspondence relating to subdivision development projects.
    - Comstock and Conjurer's Neck, 1968-1969. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Hidden Hills and Sabet Hills, 1972-March 1975. (Box 6, Folder 2-4)
    - Hidden Hills and Sabet Hills, April 1975-1976. (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
    - Hidden Hills and Sabet Hills, undated miscellaneous documents. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Aerial photos. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Series IV. Project Files, 1941-1990. (Box 22-25, Folder 1-93)
  This series contains project files with plans and drawings, which are filed into flat archival folders and are contained in oversize map case drawers unless specified elsewhere. Subseries IV.A contains a chronological arrangement of Nickels's early work from her initial training to her work at Camp Lee and Binswanger. Subseries IV.B holds sketches, plans, and elevations of her work at Marcellus Wright & Son. Designs for projects with Torrence, Dreelin & Associates are filed chronologically in Subseries IV.C. Beth often committed to freelance work or work for contemporary architects. These projects are arranged chronologically with the firm listed if known in Subseries IV.D. The end of this subseries holds work with unknown dates or firms, filed as Miscellaneous Folders. Project files that are rolled or are oversized are specified within the description and are contained in 1 of 4 oversize telescope boxes (Boxes 22-25). Subseries IV.E is arranged by year and holds student projects from Nickels's career at Richmond Technical Center. These works range from early teacher exercises to students' final exams.
  Note to Archives Reference: Each oversize folder has its own record in Infolinx. Search Box/Volume/Folder Number field using folder numbers f001, f002, etc., through f093.
  - Subseries IV.A. - Early drafting classes, Binswanger Glass, and Camp Lee.
    Drawings, maps, plans, and sketches from early drafting classes, Binswanger Glass, and work for the Post Engineer at Camp Lee.
    - Drafting practice drawings for night school at Hopewell High, Hopewell, Virginia, 1941. (Map-case 8, Drawer 11, Folder 1)
    - Maps and plans of existing buildings at Camp Lee, Post Engineer's Office at Camp Lee, Hopewell, Virginia, 1944-1947 (rolled). (Box 25)
    - Peoples Furniture Company, Binswanger Glass Company, Richmond, Virginia, 1947. (Map-case 8, Drawer 11, Folder 2)
    - Rockingham Clothiers, Binswanger Glass Company, Richmond, Virginia, 1947. (Map-case 8, Drawer 11, Folder 3)
    - Maps of City of Claremont, Virginia, Post Engineer's Office at Camp Lee, Hopewell, Virginia, 1947. (Map-case 8, Drawer 11, Folder 4)
    - G.C. Murphy, Binswanger Glass Company, 4th & Broad Street, Richmond, Virginia, 1947. (Map-case 8, Drawer 11, Folder 5)
  - Subseries IV.B. - Marcellus Wright & Son.
    Drawings, plans, and sketches by project for Marcellus Wright & Son.
    - Residence, Goodwin Street, Williamsburg, Virginia, 1948. (Map-case 8, Drawer 11, Folder 6)
    - Residence, Chesterfield, Virginia, 1948 (blueprints). (Map-case 8, Drawer 11, Folder 7)
    - Residence, Old Orchard Lane, Hill Crest, Richmond, Virginia, 1950-1952 (blueprints). (Map-case 8, Drawer 11, Folder 8)
    - Medical offices, 2306 Monument Avenue, Richmond, Virginia, 1951 (blueprints). (Map-case 8, Drawer 11, Folder 9)
    - Residence, Williamsburg, 1951 (rolled). (Box 22)
    - Chamberlain Hotel, Proposed Fenestration Changes, Hampton, Virginia, 1952. (Map-case 8, Drawer 11, Folder 10)
    - Residence, Hopewell, Virginia, 1952. (Map-case 8, Drawer 11, Folder 11)
    - Residence, Warwick-on-the-James, James River Drive, Warwick, Virginia 1953 (rolled). (Box 22)
    - Residence, 213 Lock Lane, Windsor Farms, Richmond, Virginia, 1954 (blueprints). (Map-case 8, Drawer 11, Folder 12)
    - Residence, 5 Greenway Lane, Hampton Gardens, Richmond, Virginia, 1954. (Map-case 8, Drawer 11, Folder 13)
    - Residence, Dover & Nottingham, Windsor Farms, Richmond, Virginia, 1955. (Map-case 8, Drawer 11, Folder 14)
    - Post exchange and cafeteria, Fort Lee, Virginia, 1955 (blueprint). (Map-case 8, Drawer 11, Folder 15)
    - Residence, Tempsford Lane, Richmond, Virginia, 1955. (Map-case 8, Drawer 11, Folder 16)
    - Dixie Hospital, Hampton, Virginia, 1956. (Map-case 8, Drawer 11, Folder 17)
    - Dixie Hospital, Hampton, Virginia, 1956 (rolled). (Box 22)
    - Residence, 1015 W. Franklin Street, Richmond, Virginia, 1957. (Map-case 8, Drawer 11, Folder 18)
    - Residence, 15 Tapoan Road, Richmond, Virginia, 1959. (Map-case 8, Drawer 11, Folder 19)
    - Residence, Chesterfield, Virginia, undated. (Map-case 8, Drawer 11, Folder 20)
    - Residence, unidentified location, undated. (Map-case 8, Drawer 11, Folder 21)
    - John Randolph Hospital, Hopewell, Virginia, undated. (Map-case 8, Drawer 11, Folder 22)
    - Jahnke Road School, Richmond, Virginia, undated. (rolled) (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous unidentified drawings and plans, undated. (Map-case 8, Drawer 11, Folder 23)
  - Subseries IV.C. - Torrence, Dreelin & Associates.
    Drawings, plans, and sketches by project for Torrence, Dreelin & Associates.
    - Residence, Breezy Point Farm, Goochland County, Virginia, 1961-1963. (Map-case 8, Drawer 12, Folder 24)
    - Kingsland Property Corp., Rt. 1 & Rt. 656, Chesterfield County, Virginia, 1962 (damaged). (Box 23)
    - Offices, 1112-1116 East Main Street, Richmond, Virginia, 1963. (Map-case 8, Drawer 12, Folder 25)
    - Church of God, Chesterfield County, Virginia, 1963. (Map-case 8, Drawer 12, Folder 26)
    - Montpelier Office Building, Montpelier, Virginia, 1964. (Map-case 8, Drawer 12, Folder 27)
    - Owens, Minor & Bodeker, Inc. warehouse and office, Bethlehem Road & Staples Mill Road, Richmond, Virginia, 1964 (rolled). (Box 23)
    - Post office at Montpelier, Virginia, 1964. (Map-case 8, Drawer 12, Folder 28)
    - Offices, 2nd & Cary, Richmond, Virginia, 1964. (Map-case 8, Drawer 12, Folder 29)
    - M & M Industries, warehouse and offices, Ashland, Virginia, 1964. (Map-case 8, Drawer 12, Folder 30)
    - Southern States Norfolk Service, Chesapeake, Virginia, 1965. (Map-case 8, Drawer 12, Folder 31)
    - Morgan's Drug Store, Gloucester, Virginia, 1965. (Map-case 8, Drawer 12, Folder 32)
    - Baptist Hospital (proposed), Jiblah, [Yemen], 1966. (Map-case 8, Drawer 12, Folder 33)
    - Pat's One Stop, Wholesale Phonographic Records, 17th & Venable Streets, Richmond, Virginia, 1967. (Map-case 8, Drawer 12, Folder 34)
    - Ukrop's Supermarket, Hull Street Road, Chesterfield, Virginia, 1967. (Map-case 8, Drawer 12, Folder 35)
    - E.R. Carpenter Company, 2400 Jefferson Davis Highway, Richmond, Virginia, 1967. (Map-case 8, Drawer 12, Folder 36)
    - New Plant Globe Building Corporation, Lanvale Avenue, Richmond, Virginia, 1967. (Map-case 8, Drawer 12, Folder 37)
    - E.R. Carpenter Company of North Carolina, Logview, North Carolina, 1968. (Map-case 8, Drawer 12, Folder 38)
    - Southern Biscuit Company warehouse, Myers Street, Richmond, Virginia, 1968. (Map-case 8, Drawer 13, Folder 39)
    - Addition to residence, Osborne Turnpike, Henrico County, Virginia, 1968. (Map-case 8, Drawer 12, Folder 40)
    - Commercial building, Mr. E.W. Rose, unidentified location, undated. (Map-case 8, Drawer 13, Folder 41)
    - Thalhimers, Inc. warehouse, Westmoreland Street, Richmond, Virginia, undated. (Map-case 8, Drawer 13, Folder 42)
    - Spencer Casket Company, Chamberlayne Avenue, Richmond, Virginia, undated. (Map-case 8, Drawer 13, Folder 43)
    - Grater Motor Company, Petersburg, Virginia, undated. (Map-case 8, Drawer 13, Folder 44)
    - Miscellaneous unidentified drawings and plans, undated. (Map-case 8, Drawer 13, Folder 45)
    - Miscellaneous cornice and staircase designs, undated (rolled). (Box 23)
  - Subseries IV.D. - Miscellaneous and unidentified firms.
    Drawings, plans, and sketches by project for miscellaneous firms, some of which are unidentified.
    - Residence, Sunnyside, Hopewell, Virginia, residence of Mr. and Mrs. Sam Nickels, 1950. (Map-case 8, Drawer 13, Folder 46)
    - Residence, unidentified firm, Thom Road, Richmond, Virginia, 1954. (Map-case 8, Drawer 13, Folder 47)
    - Residence, James Scott Rawlings AIA, Architect, 4503 Coventry Road, Windsor Farms, Richmond, Virginia, 1955. (Map-case 8, Drawer 13, Folder 48)
    - Plat of Mary Burnett property, L.D. Pritchard Civil Engineer and Surveyor, Prince George County, Virginia, 1958. (Map-case 8, Drawer 13, Folder 49)
    - Appomattox Manor, unidentified firm, City Point, Virginia, 1958. (Map-case 8, Drawer 13, Folder 50)
    - Bethlehem Congregation Christian Church, unidentified firm, Prince George, Virginia, 1959. (Map-case 8, Drawer 14, Folder 51)
    - Monroe Park 'otel, Virginia Elevator Company and Budina & Freeman Architects, Richmond, Virginia, 1960. (Map-case 8, Drawer 14, Folder 52)
    - Residence, Frederick Hyland AIA, Architect, unidentified location, 1960. (Map-case 8, Drawer 14, Folder 53)
    - Motel residences, Miller Homes, Miller Manufacturing Company, 1961-1962. (Map-case 8, Drawer 14, Folder 54)